const qBank = [
	{
		id: 1,
		question: "The ratio of width of our National flag to its length is___________",
		options: ["2:3", "3:2", "3:3", "4:3"],
		answer: "2:3",
	},
	{
		id: 2,
		question: "Apart from India, in which of the following two countries, Tamil is an official language?",
		options: ["Mauritius and Malaysia", "Sri Lanka and Mauritius", "Malaysia and Indonesia", "Sri Lanka and Singapore"],
		answer: "Sri Lanka and Singapore",
	},
	{
		id: 3,
		question: "The name of flame that burns day and night is known as",
		options: ["Ellora", "Ajanta", "Amar Jawan Jyoti", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Amar Jawan Jyoti"
	},
	{
		id: 4,
		question: "The word Tirthankara is related to which religion?",
		options: ["Christianity", "Buddhism", "Hinduism", "Jainism"],
		answer: "Jainism"
	},
	{
		id: 5,
		question: "'Madhubani', a style of folk paintings, is popular in which of the following states in India?",
		options: ["Bihar", "Rajasthan", "Madhya Pradesh", "Uttar Pradesh"],
		answer: "Bihar"
	},
	{
		id: 6,
		question: "In which of the following festivals are boat races a special feature?",
		options: ["Rongali Bihu", " Navratri", "Pongal", "Onam"],
		answer: "Onam"
	},
    {
		id: 7,
		question: "The paintings in the Ajanta and Ellora caves are indicative of the development of art under the -",
		options: ["Pallavas", "Rashtrakutas", "Chalukyas", "Pandyas"],
		answer: "Chalukyas"
	},
	
	{
		id: 8,
		question: " The ‘Kathakali’ dance is a harmonious combination of ______ forms of fine art.",
		options: ["5", "8", "7", "3"],
		answer: "5"
	},
	{
		id: 9,
		question: "Which among the following temples of India is known as 'Black Pagoda'? ",
		options: ["Brihadeeshwara Temple, Tanjore", "Sun Temple, Konark", "Meenakshi Temple, Madurai", "Jagannath Temple, Puri"],
		answer: "Sun Temple, Konark"
	},
	{
		id: 10,
		question: "The______dish is one of the most  popular dishes of Kashmir?",
		options: ["Dum Aloo", "Kesar Chawal", "Murgh Achaari", "Aloo Ka Raita"],
		answer: "Dum Aloo"
	},
	{
		id: 11,
		question: "Which classical dance is famous in Tamil Nadu?",
		options: ["Bharatanatyam", "Mohiniattam", "Kuchipudi", "Kathakali"],
		answer: "Bharatanatyam"
	},
	{
		id: 12,
		question: "Kumbh Mela is held in every ___ years",
		options: ["12", "7", "4", "9"],
		answer: "12"
	},
	{
		id: 13,
		question: "Dandia’ is a popular dance of _______________ .",
		options: ["Arunachal Pradesh", "Goa", "Gujarat", "Chhattigarh"],
		answer: "Gujarat"
	},
	{
		id: 14,
		question: " The Kala Ghoda Arts Festival is associated with which one of the following cities?",
		options: ["Delhi", "Jammu", "Mumbai", "Haryana"],
		answer: "Mumbai"
	},
	{
		id: 15,
		question: "‘Panchatantra’ is originally written by _____________.",
		options: ["Kalidas", " Vishnu Sharma", "Tulsi Das", "None of these"],
		answer: "Vishnu Sharma"
	},
	{
		id: 16,
		question: "Which of the following places is famous for Chikankari work, which is a traditional art of embroidery?",
		options: ["Hyderabad", "Lucknow", "Mysore", "Nagaland"],
		answer: "Lucknow"
	},
	{
		id: 17,
		question: "In which of the following city Elephant festival is celebrated annually?",
		options: ["Jaipur", "Jodhpur", "Kota", "Ajmer"],
		answer: "Jaipur"
	},
	{
		id: 18,
		question: "Veeragase is a folk music from Carnatic based on which theme of the story?",
		options: ["Based on Hindu mythology", "Based on Sufi movements", "Based on traditional values", "Based on agricultural activities"],
		answer: "Based on Hindu mythology"
	},
	{
		id: 19,
		question: "In which of the following, art painting is done by pen?",
		options: ["Phad", "Rangoli", "Kalamkari", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Kalamkari"
	},
	{
		id: 20,
		question: "Which of the following is not a harvest festival?",
		options: ["Lohri", "Bihu", "Chatth", "Pongal"],
		answer: "Chatth"
	},
	{
		id: 21,
		question: "Where did the first International film festival of India held?",
		options: ["Pune", "Himachal Pradesh", "West Bengal", "Mumbai"],
		answer: "Mumbai"
	},
	{
		id: 22,
		question: "Garo and Khasi are languages spoken in which Indian state?",
		options: ["Sikkim", "Meghalaya", "Kohima", "Tripura"],
		answer: "Meghalaya"
	},
	{
		id: 23,
		question: "Who composed the famous song “Sare Jahan SeAchha”?",
		options: ["Muhammad Iqbal", "Rabindranath Tagore", "Jaidev", "Bankim Chandra Chattopadhyay"],
		answer: "Muhammad Iqbal"
	},
	{
		id: 24,
		question: "Bhangra is the folk dance of which Indian state",
		options: ["Maharashtra", "Haryana", "Punjab", "Manipur"],
		answer: "Punjab"
	},
	{
		id: 25,
		question: "The famous 'Ganga Saga Mela', an annual fair is held in which state of India?",
		options: [" Uttar Pradesh", "Kerala", "Bihar", "West Bengal"],
		answer: "West Bengal"
	},
]

export default qBank;
